这边门打不开了
This door won't open.
我这边也是
Yeah, mine won't either.
门框被撞变形了
I think the crash bent the frame.
我们得找点东西把玻璃打碎
We need something to break the glass.
我的枪
My gun.
卡塞尔  我
Castle, I can't...
我找不到
I can't find it.
可能是我们撞车的时候被撞飞了
I-I think it got knocked out when we got hit.
帮我找找
Help me look for it.
我被卡住了
I'm stuck.
什么叫你被卡住了
What do you mean, you're stuck?
我的安全带打不开了
I mean, my belt is jammed.
座位也动不了
And the seat won't move.
刀子呢  你有刀吗
Okay, what about a knife? Do you have a knife?
有
Yeah.
在后车厢里
In the trunk.
听着  我们没时间了
Okay, look, we're running out of time.
你得看看能不能找到枪
I need you to see if you can find that gun,
然后我们把安全打断
and we'll just shoot the belt off.
我摸不到
I can't feel it.
-卡塞尔  -等等  等等
- Castle. - Okay, hang on. Hang on.
待着别动
Okay. Just stay here.
我找到了
I found it.
卡塞尔
Castle?
Castle!
我想有女儿在犯罪现场的好处
I guess the good thing about having your daughter at crime scenes is,
就是她能给你带干衣服
she can bring you dry clothes.
谢了
Thanks.
还有
And, um...
谢谢
Thanks.
你也会为我这么做的
You'd have done the same for me.
是啊
Yeah.
可能吧
Probably.
我只是庆幸你找到了我的枪
I'm just glad you found my gun.
车掉水里这种桥段
That whole, uh, sinking car thing--
看电影比亲身体验爽多了
much cooler in movies than it is in real life.
我也想说  我还是更喜欢间谍片而不是参与其中
And for the record, I prefer watching spy thrillers to being in them.
好吧
So...
老实交代
Tell me...
为什么死者长得那么像
How can your victim look like Nelson Blakely
本应死了十年的尼尔森·布莱克利
when he supposedly died ten years ago?
是啊  我
Yeah, I...
是啊  很奇怪不是吗
Yeah, weird, isn't it?
是  奇了怪了
Yeah. Weird.
假死  汽车落水
Fake deaths, car in the water--
你们就不觉得现在
Don't you think now is a good time
应该告诉我们到底怎么回事吗
to tell us what the hell is going on?
不好意思  哈维尔
Uh... I'm sorry, Javi.
机密行动
It's classified.
我在特种部队待过
I was special forces.
机密行动以前是我的家常便饭
I used to eat classified for breakfast.
这个作家小子为什么就能知道
And yet writer boy can know?
好吧  我去那边跟海港巡逻队一起
Okay. I'll be over there with harbor patrol
看怎么把你的车从水里捞出来
trying to figure out how to get your unit out of the drink.
很高兴你们没事
I'm glad you're okay.
谢谢
Thank you.
作家小子
Writer boy?
-你觉得凶手是盖奇  -对
- So you think our shooter was Gage? - Yeah.
我觉得他在除掉每一个
I think he's getting rid of anyone
会暴露他变节行动的人
that could expose his rogue operations.
他干的真是不错啊
Well, he's doing a pretty good job.
我们到现在都不知道潘朵拉是什么
We still have no idea what Pandora is.
我们知道布莱克利害怕了
Well, we know that Blakely was afraid.
我们也知道他在进行一些
And we know that he was working on something
足以威胁国家未来的研究
that was big enough to threaten the future of this country.
我们只是不知道他在研究什么
We just don't know what the hell he was working on.
他的生活中一定有些线索
There's gotta be a clue somewhere in his life.
或许他尸体能泄露点玄机
Maybe there's something on the body that will tell us.
不  我们检查过了  他兜里什么都没有
No. We checked. There was nothing in his pockets.
不过从衣兜被翻出来的样子可以猜测
But the way they were turned out makes me think
有人翻找过并把里面的东西拿走了
someone went through and emptied them.
盖奇
Gage.
莱恩  找人搜查一下建筑物
Ryan, get some teams to search the building.
-我们要找什么  -我也不知道
- What are we looking for? - I don't know.
但是他带我们过来总是有原因的
But he brought us here for a reason.
蕾妮  你能不能从他身上发现点什么
Lanie, see what you can find on him--
牙齿  伤疤  指纹  纹身
Dental, scars, prints, tattoos,
任何能告诉我们
anything that might tell us--
-他死了  -是啊
- He's dead. - Yeah.
听着  我能解释
Look, I can explain.
上车
Get in the car.
你们在做什么
What the hell did you think you were doing?
你想让我们做的  找布莱克利
What you wanted, finding Blakely.
你破解了他的密码就不想着来告诉我一声吗
You cracked his code and you didn't even think to notify me?
我得为卡塞尔说句话
Look, in Castle's defense,
这事希望渺茫
it was a long shot,
他不想自己判断错误而浪费了你的时间
and he didn't want to waste your time if he was wrong.
何况当时我们正要带他过来
And we were bringing the guy in...
却被人杀了  还是在你的监护下
When he was killed, in your custody.
你们在码头做什么
What were you doing at the docks?
-他让我们带他去的  -为什么
- He asked us to take him there. - Why?
我们不知道
We don't know.
你们问出任何事来了吗
Well, did you learn anything?
问出来了
Yes.
他受雇分析美国的弱点
He was hired to analyze the United States for vulnerabilities.
他说他发现了经济方面的一个漏洞
He said he found a weakness in our economy--
一个令人意想不到的关键
an unexpected linchpin--that,
如果有人攻击此处  多米诺骨牌就会接连倒下
if someone went after it, would start the dominos falling.
会引发什么后果
Falling toward what?
给国家带来毁灭
The end of our country as we know it.
那我们下一步做什么
So what's our next move?
没有下一步了
There is no next move.
至少你们俩没有
Not for you two.
让你们参与此事就是个错误
It was a mistake bringing you into the loop.
我本来以为
You know, I really thought--
我以为你有改变
I really thought you had changed.
结果呢
But you know what?
你还跟以前一样
You are the same reckless,
是个鲁莽  幼稚  自我为中心的混蛋
immature, self-centered jackass that you always were,
你将整个调查置于危险之中
and you've put this investigation at risk.
-对不起  -对不起
- Look, I'm sorry- - You're sorry?
我们面临的是下一个911  或许更糟
We are on the verge of the next 9/11 or worse.
这不是你写的书  里克
This isn't one of your damn books, Rick.
这是真实生活  如果出了问题
This is real life, and when things go bad,
你不能像对我们的事那样改写个结局了事
you can't just rewrite the ending like you did with us.
把他们带出去
Get them both out of here.
这么说  你跟她睡过了
So...You slept with her.
是是  我跟她睡了
Yeah, yeah. Yeah, I slept with her.
还有别人吗
Have there been others?
-女人吗  -你的缪斯
- Women? - Muses.
没了  怎么
No. Why?
我就想看看缪斯俱乐部到底有多少人
I just wanted to see how big the club was. That's all.
同志们  有进展吗
Hey, guys. What do you got?
首先  根本就没有这么个俱乐部
First off, there is no club.
其次  我们不跟这个案子了  记得吗
And second, we're off the case if you recall.
是不跟他们查了  我自己还有个凶杀案
We're off their case. I still have a murder to solve.
可你的主要嫌疑犯恰好
Where your chief suspect
是中情局行动中牵涉到的人
is smack-dab in the middle of a CIA operation.
我才不管他牵涉到哪里
I don't care what he's in the middle of.
托马斯·盖奇杀了三个人
Thomas Gage killed three people.
其中一人当时还是由我监护
One of them was in my custody.
他把我们关在车后备箱里
He locked us in a trunk
他还把我的警车撞进了哈德逊河里
and then he sent my cruiser to the bottom of the Hudson.
盖奇是个训练有素的秘密特工
Gage is a trained covert operative.
你不可能抓到他的
There's no way you can catch him.
我可以  只要想出来他下面会去哪
Yes, I can, if I figure out where he was going.
我们查明布莱克利在研究什么
We find out what Blakely was working on,
从而找到那个关键点
we find the linchpin.
找到关键点  就能找到盖奇
We find the linchpin, we find Gage.
在仓库找到什么了吗
Anything on the warehouse?
有啊  你们俩走了之后  联调局的人来了
Yeah, right after you guys left, the feds showed up
中止了我们的调查
and shut us down.
不过我们查到了死者尼尔森·布莱克利的一些信息
But we did find something on your vic Nelson Blakely.
他的指纹和长岛的斯科特·麦克格雷格相吻合
His prints came back as a Scott McGregor from long island city.
问题是  这个麦克格雷格貌似只存在于文件上
Problem is, McGregor seems to only exist on paper.
我们在现实世界里查不到他的踪迹
We can't find any trace of him in the real world.
你们派人去列出的地址盘查了吗
Did you guys send units to the listed address?
去了  住在那的人说从没听说过他
Yeah, and the family living there had never heard of him,
也没人认得他的照片
and no one recognized his photo.
肯定有人认识他
Well, someone must have known him.
是有人认识
Someone did.
他玩象棋  象棋没法一个人玩
He plays chess. That's not a solo sport.
你不是不跟这案子了吗
I thought you were off the case.
你听到索菲亚怎么说我的了
Well, you heard what Sophia said.
一个鲁莽  幼稚  自我为中心的混蛋
I'm a reckless, immature, self-centered jackass.
如果你固执到一定要继续查的地步
If you're stubborn enough to keep going,
那我就笨到跟着你继续的地步
I'm stupid enough to go with you.
好吧  你们去排查一下城里所有的象棋公园
All right. You guys canvass all of the chess parks in the city.
看看能不能找到跟他对过弈的人
Let's see if we can dig up some of his opponents.
什么
What?
什么叫"尸体就没来"
What do you mean, the body never arrived?
他们中途把尸体拦截了
They intercepted it at transport.
他们申请到了法院指令
Apparently, they had a court order.
不可能
That's impossible.
怎么可能这么快就申请到法院指令
How could they get a court order that fast?
我怎么知道  要不你去问问你女朋友
I don't know. Maybe you should ask your girlfriend.
女朋友
Girlfriend?
行了吧  我们确实一起睡了
Yes, okay. We slept together.
但那是很久以前了  有什么大不了的
It was a long time ago. What's the big deal?
没什么  爱跟谁睡跟谁睡
There is no big deal. Sleep with whoever you want.
多多益善
The more the merrier.
我把毒物检测报告拿来了
I have those, uh, toxicology reports you wanted.
好  放那儿吧  亲爱的
Oh, yes. Just set 'em there, sweetie.
谢谢
Thank you.
你喜欢你的新实习吧
So enjoying your new internship?
我了解到了很多新东西
Well, I'm learning a lot.
了解得太多了
Too much I think.
我还以为最恶心的部分会是死尸呢
And I thought the dead bodies were going to be the grossest part.
真幽默  晚安
Funny. Good night.
那么贝克特说的是谁
So who was Beckett talking about?
跟你无关  快去睡觉
None of your business. Now go to bed.
在码头出现的那个女的是谁
The woman at the docks, who is she?
不是谁
Nobody.
快去睡觉
Now go to bed.
我看到你看她的眼神了
I saw the way you looked at her.
她绝不是一般人
She's not nobody.
她是谁都无所谓
Well, it doesn't matter who she is
反正我们不会再见面了
because I am never going to see her again.
现在快去睡觉吧
Now go to bed.
要知道  你要是这么对我遮遮掩掩的
You know, if you're going to keep secrets from me,
我或许也会开始对你有所隐瞒
I might start keeping secrets from you, too.
你这年纪  瞒着爸爸点事也挺好的
At your age, I'm thinking, that might be a good idea.
索菲亚
Sophia.
晚上好  里克
Hello, Rick.
你怎么  做什么  你怎么进来的
How--what are you--how did-- how did you get in here?
我是中情局特工
I'm CIA.
你的小说现在还改编成漫画了
So they're turning them into graphic novels now?
是的
Yeah. Um...
第一本反响不错  他们还要改编一部
The first one did well, so they're gonna do another.
你觉得怎么样  她看上去像我吗
So what do you think, she look like me?
你到底来做什么
Uh... What are you doing here?
你们还在追查盖奇不是吗
You're going after Gage, aren't you?
没有  我们不能跟这个案子了  记得吗
No. We're off the case, remember?
还是过去的你更善于说谎
Mm. You used to be a better liar.
我知道你们在查布莱克利的化名
I know you've been looking into Blakely's aliases.
没关系  里克  我不介意
It's okay, Rick. I don't mind.
事实上  我希望你继续追查这个案子
In fact, I want you on this case.
-但  -我知道我说过什么
- But... -I know what I said,
但我也知道事关重大
but I also know what's at stake.
之前让你和贝克特加入调查
Bringing you and Beckett on board
并不是一个很受欢迎的决定
was not a popular decision,
而且由于布莱克利的死  我得表明立场
and after what happened with Blakely, I had to make a stand.
但是我知道你的能力
But I know what kind of asset you can be.
我知道不管我说什么你都会继续追查下去
I know you'll just keep digging no matter what I say.
这是你的天性
It's your nature.
你总得知道故事会有怎样的结局
You need to know how the story ends.
就像她的故事一样
Like with her.
她知道这些吗
Does she know about this?
那是...
Well, that's...
你总是喜欢玩危险游戏
You always did like playing with dynamite.
只是小心别玩火自焚
Just be careful it doesn't blow up in your face.
她与众不同
She's different.
是吗
Is she?
还是只是你一厢情愿
Or do you just think she is?
听说你们和我们一样查布莱克利进了死胡同
I heard you hit the same dead end with Blakely as we did.
我想你们或许可以试一下这条线索
I thought you might be able to try this.
这就是布莱克利去码头要找的东西
It's what Blakely was looking for at the pier.
我们是在一个放着机票  现金和假身份证的
We found it in a go bag with plane tickets, cash,
冲锋包里找到的
and some fake I.D.S.
银行账号
Account numbers?
全都是国内银行的
All from domestic banks.
鉴于布莱克利是美国公民
And since Blakely was a U.S. Citizen--
你们没有权力继续调查他
You're prohibited from looking into them.
但是你们有
But you guys aren't.
这些帐号可能指向他的雇主的身份
And those accounts may contain clues as to who hired him.
我想你仍然好奇故事的结局吧
And assuming you still want to know how the story ends...
只是这一次务必及时向我通报消息
Just keep me in the loop this time.
还有  里克
And, Rick...
尽量保住自己的性命
Try not to get killed.
我还是挺喜欢你的
I'm still quite fond of you.
小伙子们都去哪儿了
Where are the boys?
他们在象棋公园做排查
They're canvassing chess parks,
看看有没有人认识布莱克利
looking for anyone that knew Blakely.
你为什么没有跟他们一起去
And why aren't you with them?
因为我的车正躺在哈德逊河河底
Because my car is at the bottom of the Hudson,
而且除非我上交事故报告
and Gates won't issue me another one
盖茨就不肯给我配辆新车
until I write up an incident report,
可是这案子是机密所以我又不能写报告
which I can't do because this case is classified.
你笑什么
What?
没什么
Nothing.
只是  真是一个关键理论的绝佳例证
It's just, that's a perfect example of a linchpin.
这个案子可能永远不能侦破就因为
This case might go unsolved all because
你拿不到一辆车
you don't have access to a car.
不要逼我开枪打你
Don't make me shoot you.
如果你真开枪打我
Well, if you shoot me,
谁来帮你追查这条线索
who's gonna help you follow this lead?
布莱克利的银行账户信息
Blakely's bank account information.
这就是他去码头要找的东西
It's what he was going for on the pier.
如果我们能追踪他的资产
If we can track his money--
你从哪里得到这个的
Where did you get that?
索菲亚
Sophia.
她昨晚去了我家
She came to my place last night.
-不是你想得那样  -当然不是
- Not like that. - No, of course.
她不是说你是"鲁莽  幼稚
So then what happened to "Reckless, immature,
自我为中心的混蛋"吗
self-centered jackass"?
她只是在同事面前表一下姿态
She was posturing for her colleagues.
贝克特  这是一条线索
Beckett, it's a lead.
她希望我们继续追查此案
She wants us on the case.
你觉得到底发生了什么事
What do you think this is about, huh?
感觉像是情报部门的活动
It smells like an intelligence op.
中情局  国安局还是国土安全部
CIA, NSA, DHS?
就那几个字母排列组合
Same letters, different alphabet.
我以前部队里有些兄弟自愿参加情报部门行动
I had some buddies from the service volunteer for intelligence ops.
他们喜欢这份工作吗
Yeah, how'd they like it?
他们都牺牲了
They all died.
你们认识这个人吗
Hey, guys. Do you recognize this man?
我还真认识他
Matter of fact, I do.
他大概每周会来这公园两三次
Uh, he comes to the park two or three times a week.
找人一起下棋
Looks for games.
你还知道些什么
What do you know about him?
他是一个疯狂的棋手
He's a crazy chess player.
经常棋出怪招
Makes some weird moves,
比如牺牲皇后
like sacrificing his queen
只想看看会发生什么
just to see what happens.
但是他总是会赢
He always wins, though.
你知道他的名字吗
Do you know his name?
叫斯科特什么的
Scott or something like that.
但是如果你们想多了解一下这个人
But I-if you want to know about this guy,
你们应该去找雅尼聊聊
you should talk to Jani.
雅尼是谁
Jani? Who's Jani?
另一个棋手
Another player.
他跟你们要找的这个人
Him and your guy...
最近经常聚在一起
been spending a lot of time together lately.
布莱克利的六个账户总计有两百万
So Blakely had over $2 million in six accounts,
但都是用假名开户
and none of them under his real name.
往里面存款的都是非营利性组织  援助协会
Deposits were made by nonprofits, aid groups,
还有环保组织
environmental organizations.
如果这些真是他的秘密咨询业务账户
So if those were his secret consulting accounts,
那么这些交易中极可能有一笔
it's possible that one of those payments
是支付潘朵拉计划的
was for operation Pandora.
没错  这两笔
Exactly. These two.
每笔存入五十万
Deposits of half a million dollars each.
这一笔是三个月前
This one was from three months ago,
这一笔是一个星期前
and this one was from a week ago.
是他开始和结束的报酬
His start and finish payments.
对  均来自海外账户
Mm-hmm. Both from offshore accounts.
但现在账户已关闭  是条死胡同
But they're closed. It's a dead end.
我们可能找到条有关布莱克利的线索
We may have a lead on Blakely.
公园里的人说他最近总和这人在一起
Guy in the park said he's been spending time with this man--
雅那切克·斯佰威
Janacek Spivey.
两届全国国际象棋冠军
2-time national chess champion,
现在担任国际事务学校的经济学教授
now an economics professor at the school of international affairs.
一个经济学教授
An economics professor?
你觉得与这事有关
You think it's related?
我不知道这资料是否有用
Well, I don't know if this helps,
但他还是国际货币基金组织
but the guy is also an advisor to the I.M.F.,
联合国经济委员会以及
the U.N. Economics Council,
国会财政委员会的顾问
and the congressional finance committee.
对  就是他
Yeah, that's him.
但他说自己叫麦克格雷格  不是布莱克利
But he said his name was McGregor, not Blakely.
你对他了解多少
What do you know about him?
他是个非常厉害的棋手
Um, he was a hell of a chess player.
在我落子之前  他似乎总能洞察
Uh, it seemed like he knew every move I was gonna make
我要走的每一步
before I made it.
不  我是说...
No, I mean...
关于他个人
Personally.
其实他从没聊过他个人的事
He never really talked about his personal life.
有目击者称你们常聊天  谈了什么
Witnesses said you spent a lot of time talking. What about?
经济学理论
Economic theory.
在知道我的职业之后
When he found out what I did,
他就问了我一大堆问题
he had a million questions.
什么样的问题
What kind of questions?
有关世界的经济力量
About world economic forces,
历史上的社会经济模型
historic socioeconomic models.
有时觉得他比我知道得还多
There were times it seemed like he knew more than I did.
他是个热忱的发烧友
He was quite the hobbyist.
他可不只是个发烧友
Oh, he was more than just a hobbyist.
他有特别关注过什么东西吗
Did he focus on anything in specific?
我没什么印象
Uh, not that I remember.
但他对美国经济非常关心
Though he was very concerned with the U.S.economy.
他从没提过家人或朋友吗
And he never mentioned any family or friends?
-没有  -他去哪里买东西
- No. - Anywhere he might have shopped?
有任何能看出他住哪的线索吗
Anything that might indicate where he lived?
没有  但我觉得他住在联合广场
No. B- but I think he lived in Union Square.
为什么这么说
And what makes you say that?
有次我们散步结束
After one of our walks,
我发现把棋盘忘在公园了
uh, I discovered I'd left my chess set in the park.
往回走时  我看见他走向那里的一栋楼
And on my way back, I saw him head into a building there.
你能替我们指出是哪幢楼吗
Do you think you can identify that building for us?
我想可以
I think so.
我得借下你的车
I gotta borrow your car.
对  他就住这里
Uh, yeah, this is his place right here.
但他叫芬利  不是布莱克利或是麦克格雷格
But he said his name was Finley, not Blakely or McGregor.
谢了
Thanks.
我们要找什么
What are we looking for?
报纸  电脑  电话记录  账单
Papers, computers, phone records, bills--
任何能帮我们想明白他在做什么的线索
anything that'll help us figure out what he was up to.
我觉得我找到了
Think I found it.
搞什么啊
What the hell?
税务骚乱
"Tax riots."
欧洲经济衰竭
"European economic collapse."
伊朗侵略伊拉克
"Iran invades Iraq!"
叙利亚攻击以色列
"Syria moves on Israel."
美国遣军驻台湾
"U.S. commits troops to Taiwan."
美国遣军驻中东
"U.S. commits troops to Middle East."
俄罗斯攻击东欧
"Russia moves on Eastern Europe."
这个关键要制造出怎样的后果啊
What kind of an outcome was this linchpin supposed to create?
终结我们的国家
The end of our country as we know it.
2017年8月  美国投降
预计两千七百万伤亡
第三次世界大战
A third world war.
不可能是真的
This can't be real.
没人能预言这些
No one can predict all of this.
或许不会
Maybe not,
但有些比我们聪明的人相信他能做到
but a bunch of people smarter than us think he can
也会为了掩盖这一切而杀人
and would kill to cover it up.
我发现了一个令人担忧的弱点
I found an alarming vulnerability...
看这边
Over here.
一个与经济相关的关键
A linchpin that was tied to the economy
能造成我们前所未见的
that would cause crisis and devastation
危机和破坏
beyond anything we'd ever seen.
多米诺骨牌会永不停歇地倒下去
The dominos would just never stop falling.
她是谁
Who is she?
我不知道  但就是她了
I don't know, but this is it.
她就是那个关键
She's the linchpin.
是第一块倒下的多米诺  将引发战争
The first domino to fall that... leads to war.
我把会给美国
I gave them the blueprint
带来毁灭的蓝图交给了他们
that will bring out the end of our country as we know it.
"关键"杀手
已出现
我得给他们打电话  他们得知道这个
I have to call them. They have to know.
挂掉电话
Put the phone down.
-盖奇  -快挂电话
- Gage? - Put the phone down now.
快跑
Now run.
-什么  -跑
- What? - Run!
我以为你是坏人
I thought you were the bad guy.
如果我是坏人  你们现在早死了
If I were the bad guy, you'd be dead by now.
这边走
This way.
不  我的车就在外面
No, my car is out front.
他们盯着你的车呢  你出去就必死无疑
They're watching your car. You go that way, and you'll die.
外面的人是谁
Who's out there? Who are they?
知道答案和活着出去二选一
You can have answers or you can live.
你来选吧
Your choice.
趴下
Stay down!
我们得联系中情局的联络人
We need to call our CIA contact.
我们得告诉他们发生了什么
We need to tell them what's going on.
不许打电话
No calls.
我们在哪里
Where are we?
安全的地方  但我们没多少时间了
Someplace safe, but we don't have much time, all right?
我潜逃之前也听到了风声
I've been on the grid, I've heard the chatter.
不管到底是什么事  都将于明天发生
Whatever this is, it's going down tomorrow.
你们比我先到布莱克利家  目标是谁
Now you got to Blakely's before me. Who's the target?
你为什么杀了布莱克利和麦格拉
Why did you kill Blakely and McGrath?
我没杀他们
I didn't.
你还想让我再夺你一次抢吗
Come on. You really want me to take that gun away from you again?
-我们没时间了  -挤点时间
- We don't have the time. - Make time.
做为一个特工
Look, as an asset,
你必须训练出一些生存技能
you have to develop certain survival skills, all right?
最首要的能力
Chief of which is the ability
就是发觉情况不对劲  即使原因不明
to know something's wrong without knowing why.
通常是些小事情
It's always something small--
安全屋的电话有稳定的杂音
A static pop on your safe house phone,
刷卡时略微的延迟
a slight delay in authorization using your credit cards,
或是在和联络员谈话时
or the almost imperceptible pauses
几乎察觉不到的停顿
in conversations with your handler.
就知道情况不妙
Something's wrong,
如果你不查明是什么事
and if you don't figure out what,
你就活不过这周
you're not gonna survive the week.
现在  有人在一步步地把世界
Now someone is trying to send this world
引向战争
spiraling towards war,
他们想让我做替罪羊
and they want me to take the fall,
但这两件事他们都休想得逞
but neither of those things are gonna happen.
你得把目标的姓名告诉我
Now I need you to tell me what the name of the target is.
让我先给我中情局的联系人打电话
Look, let me call my CIA contact.
-她可以帮我们  -不行
- She can help us. - No.
一切迹象表明潘朵拉是由
Everything indicates that Pandora's being funded
与东欧有关联的军工部门资助的
by military industrial concerns linked with Eastern Europe.
他们无法完成这样的行动
They can't pull off this operation,
必须有内应帮忙才有可能
all right, not without help from the inside.
探长  你还不懂吗
Detective, don't you get it?
我的自己人在陷害我
My own people are setting me up.
除非我死了  不然他们不会罢手
And they're not gonna stop until I'm dead,
我是他们的调虎离山之计
because I'm the diversion.
如果每个人都在阻止我  却没人...
Okay, if everyone's trying to stop me, then no one--
没人去阻止潘朵拉
Then no one's trying to stop Pandora.
除了我
No one but me.
我最后问你一次
Now I'm gonna ask you one last time,
目标是谁
who's the target?
你好啊  托马斯
Hello, Thomas.
这是最老的情报机关骗局了
It's the oldest intelligence con job in the book--
制造危机让你们身处险境  他好来化险为夷
Create a crisis so you can ride in just in time to save the day.
盖奇在耍你们
Gage was playing you.
他想让你们觉得他是好人
He wanted you to think that he was the good guy.
他需要你们信任他
He needed your trust.
但是他为什么问我们"关键"是谁
Yeah, but then why did he ask us who the linchpin was?
他不是应该已经知道了吗
Shouldn't he have known?
他在保护他的行动
He was protecting his op.
想要查明我们知情程度  然后再杀你们
He was ascertaining how much we knew before he killed you.
如果你说的对  而袭击只是一出戏
Well, if you're right and the attack on us was staged,
那他不可能是单独行动
then he can't be working alone.
盖奇肯定有一个同伙
Gage must have a partner.
就是说这事还没完
Which means it's not over.
消防人员没控制住布莱克利公寓的火势
Fire crews were unable to contain the blaze in Blakely's apartment.
他的研究都没了
All of his research is gone.
在所有面部识别数据库里搜索这个
I want you to run this through every facial rec database we have.
我要知道她是谁
I want to know who she is
还有一个十岁的女孩
and I want to know how the hell a 10-year-old girl
怎么会是引发战争的第一块多米诺骨牌
could be the first domino in the march toward war.
盖奇在哪里
Where's Gage?
在禁闭室
In the tank.
那个被你扔出窗外的人加里·哈勃
You know that guy you threw out the window-- Gary Harper?
他是我朋友
He was a friend.
那你就不该派他来找我
Then you shouldn't have sent him for me.
我们以前见过
You know, we've met before.
在柏林
In Berlin,
曼海姆那件事
the Mannheim business.
交货的时候你也跟西班牙人在一起
You were there at the drop-off with the Spaniard.
你很棒
You were good.
你现在在为谁卖命
So who are you working for now?
那个小女孩是谁
Who's the girl?
"关键"是谁
Who's the linchpin?
谁让我坐了冷板凳
Who put me in the cold?
谁陷害了我
Who set me up?
那么你认为中情局内有内应
So you think there's someone inside the CIA--
有个内鬼  叛徒
a mole, a traitor?
你是这么想得吗
Is that what you think?
我想你或许是对的
You know, I think you could be right.
那个人就是你
And I think it's you.
你在犯下错误
You're making a mistake.
不  你和你的同伙在犯错
No, you and your partner are making a mistake.
我没有同伙
I don't have a partner.
那个杀了麦格拉和布莱克利的人
The guy out there, the one that killed McGrath and Blakely
那个把你的朋友撞进河里
and drove your friends into the water,
正在执行潘朵拉的那个人
the one carrying out operation Pandora,
他和我不是一伙人
he's not with me.
我在港口看到他了  看他的身手
I saw him at the docks, the way he moved.
他是你们的人
He's with you.
他是中情局特工
He's CIA.
你确定他在说谎吗
Are you sure he's lying?
他没有显露出任何撒谎的身体特征
He's not expressing any of the physiological traits.
他接受过说谎训练  不会露出马脚
He's trained to lie without betraying himself.
他想挑拨我们之间的关系  让我们互相怀疑
He wants to divide us, make us suspicious of each other.
相信我  叛徒绝对是他
Trust me. There's no mole but him.
万一你判断错了  他说得是事实呢
What if you're wrong? What if he's telling the truth?
这无关紧要
That is immaterial.
现在  外面还有人
Right now, there is someone else out there,
正在准备实行潘朵拉
who is preparing to go through with Pandora,
那个小女孩是关键
and that girl is the key.
我们要找到她
We need to find her.
所有的数据库都查不到
Still negative on all databases.
她是外籍人士  可能不在我们的数据库里
She's a foreign national. She might not be in any of ours.
她的校服呢
What about her school uniform?
可以通过那个找到她吗
Can you identify her through that?
试过了  露出的校徽太少  无法辨认
We tried. There's not enough of the crest visible to identify it.
你们真的相信吗  谋杀一个小女孩
Do you really buy this, that killing a little girl
会导致美国的瓦解
could lead to the collapse of the United States?
太荒谬了
I mean, it just seems crazy.
布莱克利的第一个关键理论也很荒谬
Yeah, well, so did Blakely's first linchpin.
他们要求他制定一个非核军事战略
They asked him to develop a nonnuclear military strategy
能够瓦解苏联
that would bring down the Soviet Union.
结果发现  我们只需开支超过他们即可
Turns out, all we had to do was outspend them.
得再审讯一下盖奇
Need to take another run at Gage.
看来他是我们目前唯一线索了
Looks like he's all we've got.
封锁这里
Put us on lockdown.
禁止任何人进出
No one leaves or enters the facility.
接触烧伤  他是被近距离射杀的
Contact burns. He was shot point-blank.
怎么会没有人听到枪声
How is it that nobody heard the shot?
这间房子是隔声的
The room is soundproof.
关键问题在于
The real question is...
怎么会没人看到
how come nobody saw?
有人黑了视频流
Someone hacked the video stream.
怎么可能  你们可是中情局
How is that possible? You're the CIA.
你们的电脑是全世界最安全的
You have the most secure computers in the world.
盖奇有可能没说谎
It's possible because Gage was right.
局里有叛徒
There's a mole in the CIA,
那个人就是这个团队中的一员
and he's in this unit.
封锁完毕
Facility's locked down.
所有人员都在岗
All personnel have been accounted for.
有多少人有权限进入那个房间
How many people had access to that room?
18个
18.
长官  我已经隔离了篡改视频的子程序
Ma'am, I've isolated the subroutine used to doctor the video.
它嵌在一个蠕虫病毒里才没被发现
It was embedded in a software worm to escape detection.
就是说查不出它的来源
Then there's no way to tell where it came from.
我或许可以使用还原算法
I may be able to use a reductive logarithm
以分离出它进入系统的路径
to isolate the pathway it took through the system.
这样也许就能知道来源了
It might tell us where it was loaded.
-你能做到吗  -我试试
- You can do that? - I can try.
开始吧
Do it.
我完全不懂他们在说什么
Wow. I got no idea what they're talking about,
可这好令人好激动啊
but this is very exciting.
好了  开始追踪
There it is. Starting the trace.
找到了
Got it.
这就是上传病毒的终端地址
That's the terminal address where the virus was uploaded.
是谁的
Whose is it?
杜兰特工
Agent Trahn's.
什么  不是我
What? No.
-你们弄错了  -把手放在显眼位置
- There's been a mistake. - Get your hands where I can see them.
趴在地上  现在  快点  趴下
Get down on the ground now! Do it now! Down now!
等一下  那是个诱饵
Wait! It's a decoy.
黑客盗用了那个IP  不是杜兰
The hacker piggybacked the I.P. it's not Trahn.
那到底是谁
Then who is it?
上传病毒的那人用了杜兰的终端IP
Whoever uploaded it used Trahn's terminal I.P.
隐藏了自己的身份
to hide their I.D.
他很强  但我更胜一筹
They're good, but I'm better.
我提取出了用户的帐号密码
I've isolated the user's pass code.
我正在解码
I'm de-encrypting now.
开始进行人员比对
Run a personnel match.
马丁
Martin?
不是我  索菲
No, Soph.
我是忠诚的  你是知道的
I'm loyal. You know I'm loyal.
那把枪放下
Then put the gun down.
把枪放下
Put it down!
好的
Okay.
好吧
All right. Okay.
马丁  只要你开枪她就死  所有人后退
Martin! No! You shoot, she dies. Everyone, back up now.
-马丁  别这样  -大家后退
- Martin, don't. Don't do it. - Back up now! Back--back up now!
按那个
Hit it.
马丁  停下
Martin, don't.
马丁  别这样  马丁
Martin, don't! Martin.
马丁  把枪放下
Put the gun down, Martin.
谢了  但我更想保命
Thanks, but I'd rather live.
关掉电梯
Shut the elevator down.
连上了
I'm in.
各就各位  我把电梯降回来
Standby. I'm bringing it back down.
这你不可能会发觉
There's no way you could've known.
不可能吗  当我们刚得知"潘朵拉"
No? When we first got wind of Pandora,
是丹博格首先找到所有关联
Danberg was the one who found all the connections.
是他追踪到盖奇的
He was the one who traced it to Gage,
只为不让我们过于接近他
all so we wouldn't get too close to him.
他甚至劝我踢走你们二位
He even tried to convince me to get rid of you two.
最糟糕的是
And worst of all,
他可能不是单独行动
he may not be working alone.
潘朵拉的影响很大
The implications of Pandora are huge.
我不懂为什么我们自己人会
I don't understand how one of our own would actually
希望把我们国家甚至世界搅入战争
want to plunge the country or the world into war.
金钱  意识形态  都说不通
Money, ideology-- none of it makes any sense.
动机不重要
Well, the motives don't matter.
重要的是阻止潘朵拉
All that matters is stopping Pandora.
盖奇说他听到些风声
Gage said he picked up chatter.
他说行动明天执行
He said it's going down tomorrow.
跟我们听到的一致
We've heard the same thing,
就是说我们的时间所剩无几
which means, we don't have any time.
必须要找到小女孩
We have to find her.
我们一定遗漏了什么
Well, there's gotta be something that we missed,
某些能够帮助我们找到她的细节
some detail that'll help us figure out who she is.
我们已经在所有数据库里搜索了
We've run it through every database we have.
我们查了能查的一切
We have looked through everything.
不是一切
Not everything.
你们监控全球地形  对吧
You guys maintain a topographical survey of the earth, right?
是的  怎么
Yeah. Why?
不要搜索女孩
So don't search for the girl.
搜索这些山脉
Run the mountains.
如果知道她来自哪儿  就可以缩小搜索范围了
If we know where she's from, we can narrow down our search.
你真天才
You are a genius.
这要花多长时间
How long will this take?
地球很大
It's a big world.
我们调出了所有的位于
We've pulled anything arid
维度40度到60度之间的干旱地带
and everything above and below 60 degrees latitude,
但他们估算  可能要32个小时
but they're estimating, it could take 32 hours.
会是个漫漫长夜啊
Sounds like a long night.
我去倒些咖啡
I'll get some coffees.
他总是很体贴
He was always thoughtful.
你喜欢他
You like him.
是的  曾经
I did. Once.
你们之间发生了什么
S-so what happened?
如果你不介意的话
If you don't mind my asking.
是这样的
Well, um,
你有过
well, you ever...
认识一个人  然后立刻产生了...
meet someone and--and have that...
强烈的吸引力的经历吗
intense attraction right away...
那种张力
You know, that tension?
我们抗拒了几个月  后来
Well, we fought it for months, and then...
后来我们再也不能忍受了
And then we just couldn't stand it anymore.
但之后  感觉
But afterward, it--it was like
那种张力是我们
that tension was all we...
仅有的
had really in.
除此之外  我们之间剩下的只有
And without it, all we were left with was that...
把彼此逼疯的那些琐事
Well, those things that drove us crazy about each other.
你知道他那个人
I mean, you know how he can be.
对
Yeah.
我知道
Yeah, I do.
有时我真希望我没跟他上床
Sometimes I wish we had never slept together...
应该一直那样暧昧着
Had kept that longing.
连咖啡杯上都印着"中情局"  太酷了
Even your coffee mugs say "CIA." That is so cool.
如果我们能成功拯救世界
Well, we save the world,
也许我会给你一个
maybe I'll let you keep one.
有动力了
Incentive.
照片里的地貌与
Uh, the topography matches terrain
中国浙江省的地理形势吻合
in the Chinese province of Zhejiang,
就在杭州城外
just outside the city of Hangzhou.
靠近上海
That's near Shanghai.
找出区域内所有学校的校服徽章
Pull up all school uniform insignias from that region.
等等  右上角那
Wait. Right there on the top right corner.
它们颜色相同
They're the same color.
上海第12女子中学
Shanghai No.12 Girls' School.
学校有网址吗
Do they have a web site?
有  但有密码保护  开始解锁
It's password protected. Picking the lock now.
黑进学校的照片档案  进行面部识别
Hack into their photo archives and run facial rec.
用图片进行对照
Bring up the captions and compare.
找到了  米娅·冈宏
Got her. Mia Ganghong.
有关于她的资料吗
What do we know about her?
不是很多
Uh, not much.
仅知道她是祥和碧玉·冈宏的女儿
Just that she's the daughter of Xiang and Biyu Ganghong.
祥·冈宏
Xiang Ganghong?
谁是祥·冈宏
Who's Xiang Ganghong?
一个中国商人
He's a Chinese businessman.
同财政部长和
With close ties to the Finance Minister
执政党关系密切
and members of the ruling party.
为何他女儿会成为目标
Well, why is his daughter targeted?
祥能左右要职的任命
Xiang is a kingmaker.
他对政府经济政策的制定
He's extremely influential
有极大的影响力
in shaping his government's economic policy.
他靠出售中国军事装备致富
He made his fortune selling Chinese military hardware.
有时会卖给我们的敌人
Sometimes to our enemies.
但由于他支持中国购买美国国债的原因
But we left him alone because he was supportive
我们听之任之
of China's purchase of U.S. debt.
现在如果有人除掉祥
Now if someone were to take out Xiang,
对大局并无影响
not that much would change.
但如果他的女儿
But if his daughter were killed
在一场拙劣的暗杀中遇害
in a botched assassination attempt,
而中国政府又追查到了美国政府的头上
and the Chinese were able to trace it back to the U.S. Government?
进而追查到盖奇
The trail that led to Gage.
不难想象祥会利用
It's conceivable that Xiang could use
其相当的影响力
his considerable influence
只手让中国停止购买美国国债
to single handedly end China's purchase of the U.S. debt.
我们国家靠赤字开支维系
This country runs on deficit spending.
如果国家借不到钱
If--if we can't borrow money--
就不能履行国家义务
We couldn't meet our obligations,
政府就会倒闭
the government would shut down.
会被迫进行财政紧缩
Austerity measures would be imposed.
我们将丧失在全球部署军事的能力
We'd lose our ability to deploy our military around the world.
美国力量被削弱
And then with the U.S. neutralized,
我们的敌人就会
our enemies would be able
疯狂掠夺获取利益
to explore their interests unchecked.
就是这样
That's right.
还会爆发地区冲突
And there would be an explosion of regional conflicts,
其中的任何一个都能引发全球战争
any one of which could send us toward global war.
一场我们甚至没能力打赢的战争
A war that we might not even be able to win.
一块多米诺骨牌被撞倒  整个世界将会翻天覆地
One domino knocked down, the entire world changes.
我们找到祥了
We've located Xiang.
一小时前他和中国代表团
He and a chinese delegation
刚刚抵达肯尼迪国际机场
just landed at J.F.K. an hour ago.
他来纽约了
He's here?
参加麦金利大厦举行的联合国贸易会议
For a U.N. Trade Conference at the Mckinley Building.
他们在过来的路上
They're on their way there now.
长官  他女儿跟他在一起
And, ma'am, his daughter's with him.
如果现在召集
If we call it in,
我能找到安保小分队待命
I can get a protective detail waiting.
你觉得警察能够阻拦
You think your cops are gonna be able to stop
中情局训练有素的特工吗
CIA-trained operatives?
他们会送命的
They'd just end up dead.
另外  如泄露半点风声
Besides, if word of this gets out,
将会引发空前绝后的国际争端
it could spark an international incident of epic proportions.
我们得收拾残局  而不是制造事端
We need to clean up the mess, not make one.
就我们吗
We and what army?
你说过我们不能相信别人
You said we couldn't trust the others
因为他们可能同丹博格是一伙的
because they could be working with Danberg.
此处不是中情局在纽约的唯一驻点
This is not the only CIA Station in New York.
我已经叫另外一队人赶去现场
I've got another field team on its way.
封锁这里  等我消息
You seal it up until you hear from me.
禁止电话进出
No calls going in or out.
我不能冒险
I'm not taking any chances.
遵命  长官
Yes, ma'am.
科里根特工  这是贝克特探长和卡塞尔先生
Agent Corrigan, Detective Beckett and Mr. Castle.
代表团人呢
Where's the delegation?
五分钟路程
Five minutes away.
我们的人就位了吗
We in position?
走廊上部署了人  街对面也有人监视
We have teams in the lobby and spotters across the street.
丹博格呢
What about Danberg?
45分钟前他进入大厦时
A guard I.D.'ed him as having entered the building
被一名警卫认出
45 minutes ago.
已有专人就位  得到授权"见即杀"
We have crews in place authorized to take him out,
但还没找到他搭档
but we still haven't identified his partner.
无论发生何事  确保小女孩的安全
Whatever happens, keep the girl alive.
明白吗
Do you understand me?
是的  长官
Yes, ma'am.
我们要去哪
Where are we going?
这边
This way.
咱们跑这儿来干吗
What are we doing down here?
咱们不是应该去大堂吗
Shouldn't we be headed for the lobby?
卡塞尔
Castle.
抱歉
Sorry.
你这是干吗
What are you doing?
丹博格根本就不是叛徒  对吧
Danberg wasn't the mole, was he?
你才是
You are.
去杀了那个女孩  这两个人交给我
Go kill the girl. I'll take care of these two.
一直都是你吗
It was you this whole time?
恐怕是的
I'm afraid so.
那你又何必把我们带来这里呢
Then why bring us here?
何不直接把我们留在那边
Why not just leave us at the facility?
因为你从不肯善罢甘休
Because you just don't stop.
你非得了解整件事不可
You need to know the story, the whole story.
如果有些细节对不上  你就穷追不舍
And if something doesn't add up, you just don't let go.
你以为我带你们来干什么
Why do you think I brought you inside?
我是在保护这次行动
I was protecting the op.
就像你为了保护行动
Like you were trying to protect the operation
而杀了布莱克利和麦格拉
when you killed Blakely and McGrath?
你陷害了盖奇
You set up Gage.
"关键"要发挥效力
Well, for the linchpin to work,
必须让中国人怪罪美国政府
the Chinese have to blame the U.S. government.
整个行动必须追踪到中情局头上来
The operation has to trace back to the CIA.
你要掩盖自己的踪迹  就把他给杀了
And when you needed to cover your tracks, you killed him.
所以你需要其他替罪羊
So then you needed someone else.
你需要丹博格
You needed Danberg.
索菲亚
Sophia...
第三次世界大战  为什么
World War III, why?
这么说吧  这世界上有些人
Let's just say, there are certain parties
会不惜一切代价来重组这个世界
who will pay anything to reshape the world.
我不信
I don't buy it.
我认识的那个索菲亚决不会为了钱
The Sophia I know wouldn't sell out her country,
或是其它任何原因当叛国贼
not for money, not for anything.
你就错在这里  里奇
Well, that's one thing you got wrong, Rick.
给我跪下
On your knees right now.
你们俩都跪下
Both of you.
你不可能从这件事中全身而退
You're never gonna get away with this.
我当然可以
Of course I will.
我就告诉他们我们尽了全力  却还是晚了一步
I'll just tell them how we all tried to stop it and couldn't,
而你们俩则在我们执行任务的过程中遇害了
and the two of you were killed in the process,
凶手当然就是丹博格
by Danberg, of course.
别担心  我会把你俩塑造成英雄的
Don't worry. I'll make it sound heroic.
你父亲会为你感到自豪的
Your father will be very proud.
我父亲
My father?
拜托  你不会以为你当初能来中情局
Well, you don't think you gained special access
是因为你的魅力吧
to the CIA back then because of your charm.
你还真是不知情啊
You really don't know, do you?
看来你永远都不会知道了
I guess you never will.
不
No!
快走
Come on.
只有咱们三个  时间不多了
It's just us, and we're out of time.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
他没事
He's fine.
他没事  他没事
He's good. He's okay.
先生  你没事吧  你没事吧
Sir, are you all right? You all right?
-这边  -没错  也许咱们该出去透透气
- This way.  - Yeah, maybe we should go outside.
你觉得这一切到底是怎么回事
So what do you think this was all about?
他们没告诉你吗
They didn't tell you?
什么
What? Th --
他们告诉你了
They -- they told you?
她反咬我一口
Once she turned me out,
我也就很快明白了事情的真相
it didn't take long to put the pieces together.
但是我当时只能旁观
But all I could do was watch
等着她下一步行动
and wait for her to make her move.
很难相信她居然是个叛徒
Hard to believe she was a traitor.
一切都是装出来的
It was all an act.
兰利认为她有可能是前克格勃潜伏间谍
Langley thinks she may have been a former K.G.B. sleeper
苏联解散  她也就没了着落
set adrift when the Soviet Union broke up.
她留在局里是因为她无处可去
Stayed with the company because she had nowhere else to go.
直到更好的机会出现
Till a better offer came along.
你们查出来她替谁工作
Did you ever find out who she was working for,
谁才是潘朵拉的幕后黑手了吗
who was behind Pandora?
没有  就算我查出来了也不能告诉你
No, and even if I did, I couldn't tell you.
丹博格探员
Agent Danberg...
索菲亚跟我说了一些事情
Sophia said something,
她说我父亲在中情局工作
Something about my father being in the CIA.
你对此会不会也有所耳闻呢
Would you know anything about that?
我恐怕不知道
I'm afraid I don't.
抱歉
Sorry.
贝克特探长
Oh, uh, Detective Beckett.
给你
Here.
我让我的人处理了一下你的车
I had our guys, uh, take care of your car.
你把我的车从河里捞出来了
You pulled my car out of the river?
是啊  你会发现车比新的还赞
Yep. I think you will find it better than new.
谢谢
Thank you.
这是我们该做的
It's the least that we could do.
保重
Take care.
你觉得她说的关于我父亲的事
You think she was telling the truth
是真话吗
about my father?
如果是的话倒是可以解释
I mean, that would explain
他为什么突然间就人间蒸发了
why he completely disappeared.
我
I...
我认为索菲亚说了很多谎话
I think that Sophia told a lot of lies.
你肯定觉得不好受吧
Must be tough,
发现她是个叛国贼
finding out that she's a traitor,
尤其是你以她为原型创作了克莱拉·斯瑞克
especially after you based Clara Strike on her and all.
怎么说呢
Hmm. Well...
克莱拉最开始是以索菲亚为原型  但
Clara started off as Sophia, but...
她后来变得更像你
she ended up being more like you, you know --
聪明  勇猛  善良
smart, fierce, kind.
这也是我被你吸引的原因
I think that's one of the reasons I was drawn to you
像缪斯一样吸引
as a muse.
你觉得布莱克利博士
You think Dr. Blakely was right...
对关键理论的判断是对的吗
about the linchpin?
你觉得咱们真的拯救了世界吗
Do you think we actually saved the world?
我认为我们救了一个小女孩的命
I think that we saved a little girl's life,
这对我来说就足够了
and that's enough for me.